[MUSIC PLAYING]
KAYCE BASQUES: 欢迎
KAYCE BASQUES: Greetings
Chrome 71 已经到来
Chrome 71 has arrived.
这里是开发者工具的新特性
Here's what's new in DevTools.
回到 Chrome 70, 我们上线了 Live Expressions,
Back in Chrome 70, we shipped Live Expressions,
它允许你在你的 console 的上方定住一个表达式
which let you pin an expression to the top of your console
并实时监视它的值
and monitor its value in real time.
在 Chrome 71 中, 当你悬浮在一个表达式之上, 其
In Chrome 71, when you hover over a live espression that
指向一个 DOM 节点, 开发者工具会
point to a DOM node, DevTools highlights
在视口中高亮这个节点.
that node in the viewport.
创建一个 live expression, 点击
To create a live expression, click
摩多(比喻: 见下)图符的小眼睛
this little eye of Mordor icon.
输入表达式, 然后点击 UI 之外来保存它
Type the expression, then click outside of the UI to save it
这里, 我正在监听 document.activeElement, 它
Here, I'm watching document.activeElement, which
告诉我当前被聚焦的节点.
tell me what node has focus.
当我悬浮在结果之上的时候, 开发者工具
When I hover over the result, DevTools
在可视窗口中显示节点的盒模型.
shows the node's box model in the viewport.
当在 console 或者是 Elements 面板工作的时候
When working in the console or Elements panel,
你现在可以存储 DOM 节点为全局变量
you can now store DOM nodes as global variables.
假如我想快速的得到这个 button 节点的引用.
Suppose I want to quickly get a reference to this button node.
在 Chrome 71 之前, 我必须做一些技巧,
Before Chrome 71, I'd have to do something hacky,
在 DOM 树中选中节点,
like select the node in the DOM tree,
然后将 $0 赋值给 console.
then assign dollar sign 0 to a console.
现在, 你只要在 DOM 树中右击
Now, you can just right click the DOM tree
然后选择 Store as Global Variable.
and select Store as Global Variable.
如果你将节点打印至 console,
If you're logging nodes to the console,
你也可以从这里右击结果, 然后选择 Store as Global Variable.
you can right click the result and select Store as Global Variable from there, too.
HAR 文件允许你和你的同事分享网络日志.
HAR files let you share network logs with your teammates.
开发者工具HAR文件现在包含自定义的initiator和priority字段信息.
DevTools' HAR files now contain custome fields for initiator and priority information.
initiator 字段告诉你该资源为什么
The initiator field tells you why the resource was
被下载, priority 字段
downloaded, and the priority field
告诉你 Chrome 赋予该资源
tells you what download priority Chrome
什么样的下载优先级.
assigned to the resource.
想导出一个 HAR 文件, 首先捕获一些网络流量,
To export a HAR file, first capture some network traffic,
然后右击, 然后选择 Save All as HAR with Content.
then right click and select Save All as HAR with Content.
新的字段命名为 _initiator 和 _priority.
The new fields are called underscore initiator and underscore priority.
下划线意味着它们是自定义字段, 不是
The underscore means that they are custom fields, not
HAR 规范的一部分.
part of the HAR spec.
要导入一个 HAR 文件回到 DevTools.
To import a HAR file back into DevTools,
只要拖拽并且放下该文件到 Network 面板.
just drag and drop it into the Network panel.
你会发现 initiator 和 priority 列, 在输入之后, 现在
You'll notice that the inititor and priority columns now
已经正确填充.
get property populated after an input.
如果你没有看到这些列, 右击表格头部
If you can't see these columns, right click the table header
并且开启它们.
and enable them.
你现在可以从主菜单访问命令菜单.
You can now access the Command menu from the main menu.
点击这个三点图标来打开主菜单,
Click the three dots icon to open the main menu,
然后选择 Run Command.
then select Run Command.
从这里, 你可以做很多方便的东西,
From here, you can do lots of handy stuff,
比如打开面板, 打开 drawers,
such as open panels, open drawers,
改变 DevTools 的外观等等.
change the appearance of Devtools, and so on.
这里是惊喜提示.
Her's bonus tip.
要看到一个元素的事件触发, 使用 monitorEvents.
To view the event fired on an element, use monitorEvents
在该 demo 中, 我有一个大 button.
In this demo, I've got a big button.
我想要给这个 button 添加一个红色的 border
I want to add a red border to the button
在我聚焦它, 然后键入 R-E-D 的时候.
when I focus it, and then type R-E-D.
但是我不知道我为了要做这个需要的
But I don't know the names of the events
这些事件的名字.
that I need in order to do this.
所以我在 DOM 树中右击该节点
So I right click the node in the DOM tree
然后使用我们的方便的新的 Store as Global Variable 特性
and user our handy new Store as Global Variable feature
来获取一个它的引用.
to get a reference to it.
然后我调用 monitorEvents 并且传入该节点作为第一个参数.
Then I call monitorEvents and pass node as the first argument.
现在, 当我悬浮在这个 button 之上的时候,
Now, when I hover over the button,
我们看到了一堆 mouse move 和 pointer move 事件.
we see a bunch of mouse move and pointer move events.
当我点击这个 button 的时候, 我们看到这个我们都知道和喜欢的
When I click the button, we see the trusty click event,
可信任的点击事件.
which we all knoe and love.
当我按下 Tab 来聚焦该节点的时候, 我们看到了一个 focus 事件.
When I press Tab to focus the node, we see a focus event.
最后, 当我键入 R, 我们看到了 key down, key press, 和 key
Last, when I type R, we see key down, key press, and key
up 事件.
up event.
E 和 D 也是一样.
Same for E and D.
所以看起来我只需要 key press 事件来让这个特性工作.
So it looks like I just need the key press events to get this feature working.
确实如此, 这里我有一个例子
And indeed. over here I got a sample
仅仅使用 key press 事件来工作.
working using only the key press events.
当我想要停止监听 节点 的事件的时候,
When you want to stop monitoring a node's events,
调用 unmonitorEvents, 并且再次传递这个节点作为第一个
call unmonitorEvents, and pass the node as the first argument
参数.
again.
你也可以限制什么事件被
You can also limit what events get
打印, 通过传递一个数组作为第二个参数, 这里的
logged by passing an array as the second argument, where
数组的每一个元素都是你感兴趣的
each item of the array is the name of an event
一个事件的名字, 比如 key press 和 focus.
that you care about, such as key press and focus.
我们也有一些缩写代号
We also have a few shorthand codes
这可以让你一次监听一组相关事件.
that let you monitor a group of related events all at once.
例如, 传递 mouse 代号
For example, passing the mouse code
告诉 DevTools 去打印鼠标相关事件.
tells DevTools to log all mouse-related events.
查看 monitorEvents API 参考来获取更多.
Check out the monitorEvents API reference to learn more.
谢谢观看.
Thanks for watching.
六周之后在 Chrome 72 再见.
See you to six weeks for Chrome 72.
[MUSIC PLAYING]